And maybe even as you deploy it and let users use it,
甚至当你部署并让用户使用它时，
how can you track how it's doing and find any shortcomings and continue to improve the quality of the answers of your system?
你如何跟踪它的表现，发现不足之处，
并继续提高系统答案的质量呢？
And I want to share with you specifically what it feels like to build one of these systems.
我特别想和你分享
构建这些系统的感觉是什么样的。
One key distinction between what you hear me talk about in this video
你在这个视频中听我讲述的内容
and what you may have seen in more traditional machine learning, supervised learning applications is
和你在更传统的机器学习，监督学习
应用中可能看到的内容之间的一个关键区别是
because you can build such an application so quickly, the methods of evaluating it, it tends not to start off with a test set.
因为你可以快速构建这样的应用程序，
所以评估它的方法通常不会从测试数据集开始。
Instead, you often end up gradually building up a set of test examples.
相反，你通常最终会逐渐建立一套测试例子。
Let me share with you what I mean by that.
让我向你解释我这么说的原因。
You will remember this diagram from the second video about how prompt-based development speeds up the core parts of model development
你还记得第二个视频中的这个图表，它展示了
”如何通过基于提示的开发加快模型开发“
的核心部分，
from maybe months to just minutes or hours or at most a very small number of days.
从可能需要几个月到
仅仅几分钟、几小时或者最多几天。
In the traditional supervised learning approach, if you needed to collect, say, 10,000 labeled examples anyway,
在传统的监督学习方法中，如果你需要收集，
比如说，10,000个标记了的数据示例，
then the incremental cost of collecting another 1,000 test examples isn't that bad.
那么收集另外1,000个
测试示例的增量成本并不算高。
So in the traditional supervised learning setting,
所以在传统的监督学习环境中，
it was not unusual to collect a training set, collect a development set or holdout cross-validation set in the test set,
收集训练数据集、收集开发数据集、
保留交叉验证数据集和测试数据集是很常见的，
and then tap those at hand throughout this development process.
然后在整个开发过程中随时要使用这些数据。
But if you're able to specify a prompt in just minutes and get something working in hours,
但是，如果你使用Prompt-based AI，
你只要几分钟内就可以写好一个提示\（Prompt），N并在几个小时内使其工作，
then it would seem like a huge pain if you had to pause for a long time to collect 1,000 test examples
那么如果你必须暂停很长时间
去收集1000个测试示例，就会觉得非常麻烦，
So when building an application using an LLM, this is what it often feels like.
所以在使用LLM构建应用程序时，
通常会有这种感觉：
First, you would tune the prompts on just a small handful of examples,
首先，你会在少量的例子
上调整提示（Prompt），
maybe one to three to five examples, and try to get a prompt that works on them.
可能是一到三到五个例子，
尝试找到一个适用于它们的提示。
And then as you have the system undergo additional testing, you occasionally run into a few examples that are tricky.
然后，在系统调试过程中，
你偶尔会遇到一些棘手的案例。
The prompt doesn't work on them or the algorithm doesn't work on them.
提示或者算法在这些案例上不起作用。
And in that case, you can take these additional one or two or three or five examples and add them to the set that you're testing on
在这种情况下，你可以把这些额外的一两个
或三五个例子加入到你正在测试的数据集中，
to just add additional tricky examples opportunistically.
慢慢的收集更多棘手的例子
形成一个开发数据集。
Eventually, you have enough of these examples you've added to your slowly growing development set
最后，你添加到开发数据集的例子足够多了，
that it becomes a bit inconvenient to manually run every example through the prompt every time you change the prompt.
以至于每次对提示修改后，要手动
把数据集的例子挨个运行一遍都有点麻烦了。
And then you start to develop metrics to measure performance on this small set of examples, such as maybe average accuracy.
然后你可以开始制定指标来衡量
这些例子的运行情况，比如说平均准确率如何。
you can stop right there and not go on to the next bullet.
你可以就此停止，不需要再进行下一个步骤。
And in fact, there are many deploy applications that stops at maybe the first or the second bullet and are running just fine.
事实上，有很多应用可能只进行
到第一或第二步，运行得也很好。
Now if your hand-built development set that you're evaluating the model on
现在，如果你手工收集的
用来评估模型的数据集，
then that's when you may go to the next step of collecting a randomly sampled set of examples to tune the model to.
那么你可能需要进行下一步，
收集随机抽样的数据集来调整模型。
And this would continue to be a development set or a holdout cross-validation set,
这将继续作为一个开发数据集
或保留交叉验证数据集，
because it would be quite common to continue to tune your prompt to this.
因为继续调整你的提示
以适应数据集合是很常见的。
And only if you need even higher fidelity estimate of the performance of your system,
只有当你需要对系统的表现
做很高精准度的评估时，
then might you collect and use a holdout test sets that you don't even look at yourself when you're tuning the model.
你才需要收集和使用一个保留测试数据集，
通常在调整模型时，你是不应该使用
这个保留测试集的（甚至看都不要看一眼）。
And so step four tends to be more important if, say,
所以第四步在某种程度上更重要，
比如说：
your system is getting the right answer 91% of the time and you want to tune it to get it to give the right answer 92 or 93% of the time.
如果你的系统正确率为91%，
你想调整它使正确率达到92%或93%。
Then you do need a larger set of examples to measure those differences between 91 and 93% performance.
那么你确实需要更多的例子
来衡量91%和93%之间的准确率差异。
And then only if you really need an unbiased, fair estimate of how was the system doing,
只有在你真的需要一个
公正、无偏的估计来评估系统的表现时，
then do you need to go beyond the development set to also collect a holdout test set.
你才需要在开发数据集之外
再收集一个保留测试数据集。
One important caveat,
有一个重要的注意事项：
I've seen a lot of applications of large language models where there isn't meaningful risk of harm
我见过很多大型语言模型的应用，
其中如果给出的答案不太准确，
并没有实质性的危害风险。
to make sure it's doing the right thing before you use it, that becomes much more important.
确保在使用之前它能做正确的事情，
这就变得更加重要了。
then maybe the risk of harm is more modest
那么可能造成的危害风险就相对较小
and you can stop early in this process without going to the expense of bullets four and five and collecting larger data sets on which to evaluate your algorithm.
你可以在这个过程的早期就停止，
而不用花费第四和第五点的成本，
收集更大的数据集来评估你的算法。
So in this example, let me start with the usual helper functions.
所以在这个例子中，让我从常用的辅助函数开始。
Use a utils function to get a list of products and categories.
使用一个utils函数
来获取产品和类别的列表。
So in the computers and laptop category, there's a list of computers and laptops and the smartphones and accessories category.
所以在计算机和笔记本电脑类别中，
有一个计算机和笔记本电脑的列表，
还有智能手机和配件类别。
Here's a list of smartphones and accessories and so on for other categories.
这里有一个智能手机和配件的
列表，以及其他类别的列表。
But the prompt specifies a set of instructions and it actually gives the language model one example of a good output.
但是提示中指定了一组说明，
并且实际上给了语言模型一个好的输出示例。
This is sometimes called a few shot or technically one shot prompting
这有时被称为少量示例（Few-shot）
或者从技术上说是单示例提示（One-shot prompting）
because we're actually using a user message and a system message to give it one example of a good output.
因为我们实际上使用用户消息
和系统消息给它一个好的输出示例。
If someone says I want the most expensive computer, let's just return all the computers because we don't have pricing information.
如果有人说我想要最贵的电脑，
那我们就返回所有电脑，因为我们没有价格信息。
Now let's use this prompt on the customer message, which TV can I buy if I'm on a budget.
现在让我们在客户留言上使用这个提示：
“如果我预算有限，我可以买哪台电视？”
And so we're passing in to this both the prompt customer_msg_0 as well as the products and category.
所以我们把提示、customer_msg_0
和产品类别都传递给它。
This is the information that we have retrieved up top using the utils function.
这是我们在上面使用utils函数
检索到的信息。
And here it lists out the relevant information to this query, which is under the category televisions and whole theater systems.
这里列出了与此查询相关的信息，
即电视和整个影院系统类别下的信息。
This is a list of TVs and whole theater systems that seem relevant.
这是一份看起来相关的电视
和整个影院系统列表。
To see how well the prompt is doing, you may evaluate it on a second prompt.
要查看提示的效果如何，
可以在第二个提示上进行评估。
Someone says I need a charger for my smartphone.
有人说我需要一个智能手机充电器。
It looks like it's correctly retrieving this data, how to be a smartphone's accessories and list the relevant products.
看起来它正确地获取了这些数据，
如何成为智能手机配件并列出相关产品。
And here's another one.
还有另一个：
So what computers do you have?
“那么你们有哪些电脑？”
So here I have three prompts.
所以这里我有三个提示。
And if you are developing this prompt for the first time,
如果你是第一次开发这个提示，
it would be quite reasonable to have one or two or three examples like this
这样的一两个或三个例子是相当合理的
and to keep on tuning the prompt until it gives appropriate outputs
并不断调整提示，直到它给出适当的输出
until the prompt is retrieving the relevant products and categories to the customer requests for all of your prompts,
直到提示能够根据客户的请求，
检索出所有提示所需的相关产品和类别，
all three of them in this example.
就像这个例子中的所有三个提示一样。
And if the prompt had been missing some products or something,
如果提示缺少一些产品之类的东西，
then what we would do is probably go back to edit the prompt a few times until it gets it right on all three of these prompts.
那么我们可能会回去修改几次提示，
直到它在这三个提示上都正确。
After you've gotten the system to this point, you might then start running the system in testing,
在将系统调整到这个程度之后，
你可能会开始测试你的系统，
maybe send it to internal test users or try using it yourself and just run it for a while to see what happens.
也许将其发送给内部测试用户
或尝试自己使用它，然后运行一段时间
看看会发生什么。
And sometimes you will run across a prompt that it fails on.
有时候你会遇到一个它无法解决的提示。
So here's an example of a prompt.
这里有一个提示的例子。
Tell me about the SmartX pro phone and the Fotoshop camera, also what TVs you have.
告诉我关于SmartX Pro手机
和Fotoshop相机，还有你们有哪些电视。
So when I run it on this prompt, it looks like it's outputting the right data,
当我在这个提示上运行它时，
看起来它输出了正确的数据，
but it also outputs a bunch of text here, this extra junk.
但它也输出了一堆额外的垃圾文字。
It makes it harder to parse this into a Python list of dictionaries.
这使得要这段字符串很难
被解析成Python对象列表。
So we don't like that it's outputting this extra junk.
我们不喜欢它输出这些额外的废话。
then common practice is to just note down that this is a somewhat tricky example.
通常的做法就是记下
这是一个有点棘手的例子。
So let's add this to our set of examples that we're going to test the system on systematically.
那么让我们把这个加入
到我们要测试系统的例子集合里。
We did tune the prompt to three examples, so maybe it will work on many examples.
我们确实调整了三个示例的提示，
它可能会在很多例子上都能工作。
But just by chance, you might run across another example where it generates an error.
但是碰巧，你可能会遇到
另一个它产生错误的例子。
So this customer_msg_4 also causes the system to output a bunch of junk text at the end that we don't want.
这个customer_msg_4也导致系统
在最后输出了一堆我们不想要的垃圾文本。
Trying to be helpful to get all this extra text, but we actually don't want this.
试图帮助我们得到所有这些
额外的文本，但实际上我们并不需要这些。
And so at this point, you may have run this prompt maybe on hundreds of examples,
在这一点上，你可能已经
在数百个例子上运行了这个提示，
maybe you have test users, but you would just take the examples, the tricky ones, it's doing poorly on.
也许你有测试用户，但你只需要
拿那些棘手的例子，它做得不好的那些。
And now I have this set of five examples indexed from zero to four,
现在我有这一组5个例子，从0到4编号，
have this set of five examples that you use to further fine tune the prompts.
有这一组5个例子，
你可以用来进一步微调提示。
And in both of these examples, the LLM had output a bunch of extra junk text at the end that we don't want.
在这两个例子中，LLM
都输出了一堆我们不想要的额外垃圾文本。
And after a little bit of trial and error, you might decide to modify the prompts as follows.
经过一点尝试和错误，
你可能会决定修改提示如下：
So here's a new prompt, this is called prompt v2.
这里有一个新版本的提示，叫做Prompt v2。
But what we did here was we added to the prompt, do not output any additional text that's not in JSON format,
但我们在这里做的是，我们在提示中添加了：
“不要输出任何不是 JSON 格式的额外文本”。
just to emphasize, please don't output this JSON stuff.
就是强调一下：请不要输出JSON之外的内容。
And added a second example, using the user and assistant message for few-shot prompting,
并添加了第2个例子，
使用用户和助手消息进行
少量示例提示（Few-shot prompting），
where the user asked the cheapest computer.
用户询问最便宜的电脑。
And in both of the few-shot examples,
在这两个少量示例提示的例子中，
we're demonstrating to the system a response where it gives only JSON outputs.
我们向系统展示了一个示例，
这个示例只返回 JSON 格式的结果。
do not output any additional text that's not in JSON format.
不要输出任何不是JSON格式的额外文本。
to give it two of these few-shot prompts.
给它两个这样的少量示例提示。
So let me hit shift enter to find that prompt.
那么让我按shift enter找到那个提示。
And you were to go back and manually rerun this prompt on all five of the examples of user inputs,
如果你回头手动重新运行这个提示，
对所有五个用户输入示例，
you find that it now gives a correct output.
你会发现它现在给出了正确的输出。
And if you were to go back and rerun this new prompt, this is prompt version v2,
如果你回头重新运行这个新提示，
这是提示版本v2，
on that customer message example that had resulted in the broken output with extra junk after the JSON output,
在那个客户留言示例上，
之前的版本在JSON输出之后还有额外垃圾文本，
导致输出错误。
then this will generate a better output.
新版本生成了更好的输出结果。
And I'm not going to do it here, but I encourage you to pause the video and rerun it yourself on customer_msg_4 as well on this prompt v2,
我不会在这里做，但我鼓励你暂停视频，
然后自己重新运行customer_msg_4，
还有这个提示v2，
see if it also generates the correct output.
看看它是否也能生成正确的输出。
And hopefully it will, I think it should.
希望它能，我觉得应该可以。
And of course, when you modify the prompts,
当然，当你修改提示时，
it's also useful to do a bit of regression testing to make sure that when fixing the incorrect outputs on prompts three and four,
也有必要做一些回归测试，
以确保在修复提示3和4的错误输出时，
it didn't break the output on prompt zero either.
没有破坏提示0的输出。
Now you can kind of tell that if I had to copy paste five prompts, customer_msg_0, 1, 2, 3, and 4 into my Jupyter Notebook
现在你可以看出，如果我必须复制粘贴
五个提示，customer_msg_0、1、2、3和4
到我的Jupyter Notebook，
and run them and then manually look at them to see if they all put in the right categories and products,
运行它们，然后手动查看它们，
看看它们是否都放在了正确的类别和产品中，
you can kind of do it.
你可以这么做。
I can look at this and go yep, category TV and home theater systems products.
我可以看着这个说：
是的，类别是电视和家庭影院系统产品。
But it's actually a little bit painful to do this manually,
但实际上，手动做这个有点痛苦，
to manually inspect or to look at this output to make sure with your eyes that this is exactly the right output.
需要用眼睛仔细检查输出结果，
确保这确实是正确的输出。
So when the development set that you're tuning to becomes more than just a small handful of examples,
当你调整的开发集不再只有少数几个例子时，
it then becomes useful to start to automate the testing process.
自动化测试流程就变得很有用了。
So here is a set of 10 examples where I'm specifying 10 customer messages.
这里有10个例子，
我指定了10条客户留言。
So here's the customer message, what TV can I buy from a budget?
这是客户的留言，
我有预算可以买什么电视？
As well as what's the ideal answer?
还有什么是理想的答案？
Think of this as the right answer in the test set,
把这个当作测试数据集里的正确答案，
or really I should say development set because we're actually tuning to this.
或者我应该说开发数据集，
因为我们实际上是在调整这个。
And so we've collected here 10 examples indexed from zero through nine,
我们在这里收集了10个例子，
索引编号从0到9，
where the last one is if the user says I would like hot tub time machine, we have no relevant products to that, really sorry.
最后一个是：
“如果用户说我想要热水浴缸时间机器，
我们真的没有相关产品，非常抱歉。”
The ideal answer is the empty set.
理想的答案是空集。
what a prompt is doing on any of these 10 examples, here is a function to do so.
某个提示在这10个例子中的某个例子上
的运行结果，这里有一个函数可以实现。
It's kind of a long function, feel free to pause the video and read through it if you wish.
这是一个有点长的函数，如果你
愿意的话，可以暂停视频并仔细阅读。
But let me just demonstrate what it is actually doing.
让我演示一下它实际上在做什么。
Right, so customer messages, which TV can I buy if I'm on a budget?
客户留言：“如果我预算有限，
我可以买哪台电视？”
So the ideal answer is here are all the TVs that we want the prompt to retrieve.
所以理想的答案是根据提示
列出所有我们希望获取的电视。
And let me now call the prompt, this is prompt v2 on this customer message with that user products and category information.
现在让我调用这个提示，这是在
这个客户消息上使用该用户产品
和类别信息的提示符v2。
Let's print it out.
我们打印出来。
And then we'll call the eval.
然后我们将调用eval。
We'll call the eval_responsive_with_ideal function to see how well the response matches the ideal answer.
我们将调用
eval_responsive_with_ideal函数，
看看返回结果与理想答案的匹配程度如何。
And in this case, it did output the category that we wanted and it did output the entire list of products.
在这种情况下，
它确实输出了我们想要的类别，
也输出了整个产品列表。
And so it's this gives you the score of 1.0.
所以这给你一个1.0的分数。
Just to show you one more example, it turns out that I know it gets it wrong on example seven.
再给你们举个例子，
事实证明我知道它在第7个例子上出错了。
So if I change this from zero to seven and run it, this is what it gets.
所以如果我把这个从0改成7
然后运行，这就是它得到的。
Oh, let me update this to seven as well.
哦，让我把这个也更新成7。
So under this customer message, this is the ideal answer where it should output under gaming consoles and accessories.
在这个客户留言下面，
这是理想的答案，它应该输出
在”游戏机和配件“分类下面。
So this is gaming consoles and accessories.
这是游戏机和配件。
But whereas the response here has three outputs, it actually should have had one, two, three, four, five outputs.
但是这里的回应有三个输出，
实际上应该有一、二、三、四、五个输出。
And so it's missing some of the products.
它缺少了一些产品。
So what I would do if I'm tuning the prompt now is
如果我现在要调整提示的话，
I would then use a for loop to loop over all 10 of the development set examples where we repeatedly pull out the customer message,
我会用一个for循环来遍历
所有10个来自开发数据集的示例，
我们逐个获取客户留言，
get the ideal answer, the right answer, call the arm to get a response, evaluate it,
得到理想答案，正确答案，调用函数
得到返回结果，并对结果进行评估，
and then you know, accumulate it in average.
然后你知道，累积平均。
And let me just run this.
让我运行一下这个。
So this will take a while to run, but when it's done running, this is the result.
这个运行起来需要一段时间，
但当它运行完毕时，这就是结果。
We're running through the 10 examples.
我们正在浏览10个示例。
It looks like example seven was wrong.
看起来第7个示例是错误的。
And so the fraction correct of 10 was 90% correct.
所以在10个示例的测试中，
正确的比例是90%。
And so if you were to tune the prompts, you can rerun this to see if the percent correct goes up or down.
因此，如果你调整提示，
可以重新运行以查看正确百分比是上升还是下降。
What you just saw in this Notebook is going through steps one, two, and three of this bulleted list.
你刚才在这个笔记本中看到的是
完成这个项目符号列表中的第一、二、三步。
And this already gives a pretty good development sets of 10 examples with which to tune and validate the prompts is working.
这已经提供了一个相当好的
开发数据集，包括10个示例，
用于调整和验证提示是否有效。
then you now have the software needed to collect a randomly sample sets of maybe 100 examples with their ideal outputs.
那么你现在已经有了需要的软件，
可以收集一个随机抽样的示例数据集，
比如100个示例及其理想输出。
But for a lot of applications, stopping at bullet three,
但对于很多应用来说，做到第三点就足够了，
but there are also certainly applications where you could do what you just saw me do in Jupyter Notebook
像我刚才在Jupyter Notebook
做的这些，你也可以应用，
and get a pretty performance system quite quickly.
帮你快速将系统准确率优化到很好。
And again, the important caveat that if you're working on a safety critical application or
再次强调，如果你正在开发
对安全性要求很高的应用或者
an application where there's non-trivial risk of harm,
可能存在实质性伤害风险的应用，
then of course it would be the responsible thing to do to actually get a much larger test set
那么负责任的做法当然是
在任何地方使用它之前，进行
大规模的测试集验证以严格验证其准确性。
And so that's it.
就是这样。
I find that the workflow of building applications using prompts is very different than a workflow
我发现，使用提示构建应用程序
的工作流程与使用监督学习构建应用程序
的工作流程非常不同，迭代的步伐感觉快了很多。
And if you have not yet done it before,
如果你还没有尝试过这种方法，
you might be surprised at how well an evaluation method built on just a few hand curated tricky examples.
你可能会对只用几个精心策划的棘手例子
构建的评估方法的效果感到惊讶。
You think with 10 examples and this is not statistically valid for almost anything,
你可能会认为，10个例子对于几乎所有事情
来说，这在统计上都是不成立的，
but you might be surprised when you actually use this procedure, how effective adding a handful,
但你可能会在实际使用这个程序时惊讶地发现，
将一小部分棘手的例子加入到你的开发集中，
in terms of helping you and your team get to an effective set of prompts and effective system.
可能会在帮助你和你的团队得到一套
有效的提示和有效的系统方面，效果出奇的好。
In this video,
在这个视频中，
So the next video,
那么下一个视频中，
let's take a look at how you can evaluate output in that setting where what is the right answer is a bit more ambiguous.
让我们一起看看在那种
没有标准答案的情况下，如何评估输出。